<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Nejc Saje - General</title><link href="http://nejc.saje.info/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://nejc.saje.info/feeds/general.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://nejc.saje.info/</id><updated>2017-02-08T08:20:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Best Colorscheme For The Eyes</title><link href="http://nejc.saje.info/best-colorscheme-for-the-eyes.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-08T08:20:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-02-08T08:20:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Nejc Saje</name></author><id>tag:nejc.saje.info,2017-02-08:/best-colorscheme-for-the-eyes.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From time to time the coworkers who stop by my desk ask me something
along the lines of "Is that a yellow background? How can your eyes stand
that, isn't light text on a dark background better for the eyes?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='images/colorscheme.png' style="width: 750px;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a common misconception among programmers, myself included until …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From time to time the coworkers who stop by my desk ask me something
along the lines of "Is that a yellow background? How can your eyes stand
that, isn't light text on a dark background better for the eyes?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='images/colorscheme.png' style="width: 750px;"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a common misconception among programmers, myself included until
a few years back. I reasoned that since light text on a dark background
emits less light overall, it must be easier on the eyes. But that is not
actually the case, as is wonderfuly explained in this &lt;a href="http://ux.stackexchange.com/a/53268"&gt;UX StackExchange
answer&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='font-family: Arial,"Helvetica Neue",Helvetica,sans-serif'&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of research on this topic since the 1980s and a lot
of it still holds true today. One study from the 1980s states this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, most studies have shown that &lt;strong&gt;dark characters on a light
background are superior to light characters on a dark background (when
the refresh rate is fairly high)&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, Bauer and Cavonius
(1980) found that participants were 26% more accurate in reading text
when they read it with dark characters on a light background.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reference: Bauer, D., &amp;amp; Cavonius, C., R. (1980). Improving the
legibility of visual display units through contrast reversal. In E.
Grandjean, E. Vigliani (Eds.), Ergonomic Aspects of Visual Display
Terminals (pp. 137-142). London: Taylor &amp;amp; Francis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why this matters is because of focus. As this article on
UXMovement states, "white stimulates all three types of color sensitive
visual receptors in the human eye in nearly equal amounts." It causes the
eye to focus by tightening the iris. Since the eye is focused, dark
letter forms on light backgrounds are easier to read. When using a dark
background with strong light letter forms, the iris opens to allow more
light in, but that causes letter forms to blur. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People with astigmatism (approximately 50% of the population) find it
harder to read white text on black than black text on white. Part of
this has to do with light levels: &lt;strong&gt;with a bright display (white
background) the iris closes a bit more, decreasing the effect of the
"deformed" lens; with a dark display (black background) the iris opens
to receive more light and the deformation of the lens creates a much
fuzzier focus at the eye.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jason Harrison – Post Doctoral Fellow, Imager Lab Manager – Sensory
Perception and Interaction Research Group, University of British
Columbia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now there seem to be varying factors into contrast and legibility. Room
ambient lighting. Brightness of the monitor. Also you can mitigate the
straining effects of white (#FFF) on black (#000) by simply lessening the
contrast like using a light gray (#EEE, #DDD, #CCC) on a dark background
(#111, #222). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last paragraph mentions that white on black can indeed be a bit
straining on the eyes. I use &lt;a href="http://ethanschoonover.com/solarized"&gt;Solarized
Light&lt;/a&gt;, a color scheme with just the
right amount of contrast for best legibility and a background with reduced
blue light content compared to a white background. And yes, it's yellow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="General"></category><category term="programming"></category><category term="colorscheme"></category><category term="color"></category><category term="background"></category><category term="solarized"></category><category term="contrast"></category></entry></feed>